Curriculum Vitae

ALEXANDER IVANOV

Personal Details

Date of birth: December, 16, 1978

Address: Av. Libertad 269, Viña del Mar, Valparaíso, Chile

Email: 7blockchains@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/crypt0grapher

Telegram: blockchains7

Summary

Seasoned Blockchain Engineer with 25 years of hands-on software development experience across a diverse range of knowledge areas.

Developing, researching, and leading teams and projects. The last 5 years only delivering blockchain solutions mostly with Typescript, Node.js, React, Solidity and Rust. Keeping up with the most modern frameworks. Have been working with smart contracts, blockchain APIs, custom blockchains, DEXes and CEXes, algorithmic crypto trading, tokenomics, web apps, machine learning, complex corporate systems, applied cryptography, authentication software, client-server applications, containerized services, mobile and desktop apps, databases, embedded software, low-level kernel developments, and other interesting stuff.

Truly believe Substrate and Cosmos are the best blockchain SDKs. Professionally interested in building decentralized participant-owned future, comprising but not limited to DeFi. Huge fan of declarative and functional programming, applied cryptography, sailing, and table tennis. The most recent projects accomplished in 2022:

- Bridge and DEX, React, Typescript.
- Cross-platform non-custodial Mobile Wallet for iOS and Android: React Native.
- NFT game, Solidity, Typescript.
- $\bullet\,$ Protocol audit for Cosmos and EVM: Rust and Solidity.
- Trading bot on synthetic stocks: Node.js Nest.js backend and React NextJS frontend .
- Crypto banking system: GraphQL API on PostgreSQL with gate to Ethereum and Avalanche, Node.js.

SKILLS

Blockchains: Cosmos, CosmWasm (Rust, yield generator interface, DeFi protocol), Substrate (business needs tailored value-transfer blockchain), Graphene and Bitshares (C++ smart contracts, chain core updates and hardforks, upgrade and drain scripts, development of faucet, user UI), EVM (DeFi protocol and NFT game smart contracts in Solidity, JS/TS APIs), Bitcoin and Litecoin (interfaces with third-party DEX), Solana (Metaplex Candy Machine setup and configuration, program updates in Rust), . Languages, applications, and frameworks: Javascript & Typescript (Node.js/Nest.js, NextJS, React & Redux, React Native, Vue), C++ (macOS kernel and driver development, cross-platform, Qt, JUCE, mathematical computations), ObjC, Swift, C (embedded development), ASM (x86/ARM, reverse engineering), Java & Kotlin (server apps, APIs, Android development), Python (Django, Data Science and Machine Learning), Rust (tools, and COSolana programs).

Workflow: Git, GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket, CI/CD, Terraform, Kubernetes, Docker, AWS, NGINX, VPN, Apache Tomcat, Spark.

OS: Linux (Ubuntu, Redhat/CentOS), MacOS, Windows, FreeBSD, Embedded systems.

 ${\bf Databases:}\ {\rm MySQL/MariaDB},\ {\rm Postgres},\ {\rm SAP}\ {\rm ASE},\ {\rm MSSQL},\ {\rm MongoDB}.$

Data Science: TensorFlow, PySpark.

Project Management approaches and tools: Waterfall, Agile, Gantt, MS Project, Trello, Jira, ClickUp.

EDUCATION

09/1996-09/2001~ MSc, Applied Mathematics, Moscow Intitute of Physics and Technology

10/2001–08/2003 MSc, Statistical Applications, Higher School of Economics

Work experience

12/2016–present Freelancer, Blockchain Engineering.

Overview: Developing, delivering, and supporting trading bots, DeFi protocols, custom corporate blockchains, DEXes/CEXes, mobile apps, webapps, APIs, games, cryptographic verifiers. Typescript, Solidity, Rust, and C++.

09/2008-11/2016 Boutique software consulting company owner.

Overview: Software Developer, Consultant, Architect, and Manager. Delivering software projects and related services in the corporate space, list of the clients includes Deloitte, PwC, P&G, SAP SE, and many others. ERP systems implementation and development, databases development, data

pipelines, connectors, and applications. Typescript and Javascript, Node.js, C++, ABAP, Java, Python.

03/2001-04/2007 Game and educational software development.

Overview: Independent developer focused on delivering highly UI focused and realtime products, including games and educational software for learning foreign languages using voice recognition and voice databases. Using Qt, JUCE, C++, Javascript, Python.

03/1997-04/2001 High Frequency Elements Ltd., software engineer.

Overview: Signal processing and pattern recognition on embedded devices with C and Python.

03/1995–03/1997 Paragon Technologies GmbH, programmer with C/C++, x86 Assembly.

Overview: development of low-bandwidth terminal applications, drivers, and proprietary linux kernel development.

LANGUAGES

RussiannativeEnglishfluentSpanishfairFinnishbeginner